David Robles

Contact

Information Phone: 415-515-4764

E-mail: drobles@gmail.com Twitter: @davidrobles

Linkedin http://www.linkedin.com/in/drobles

Professional Summary Software Engineer and former Ph.D. student. As a software developer I believe in object oriented design and agile methodologies, and consistently employ test-driven development. I also have some interest in games programming.

My research area during my Ph.D. can be broadly described as Artificial Intelligence with a particular focus on Reinforcement Learning, Simulation-Based Search, Evolutionary Algorithms and Games.

EDUCATION

PhD Computer Science

University of Essex

Colchester, United Kingdom

2009 - 2013

Dissertation title: Simulation-Based Search and Learning in Games

MSc Computer Science

University of Essex

Colchester, United Kingdom

2007 - 2008

BSc Information Systems Engineering

Institute of Technology and Higher Education of Monterrey

Hermosillo, Mexico

2001 - 2006

SKILLS SUMMARY

Artificial Intelligence: Reinforcement Learning, Simulation-Based Search, Evolution-

ary Algorithms, Neural Networks, Game Theory.

Programming languages: Java, Ruby, Python, PHP, C.

Web Development: Ruby on Rails, PHP, JSP/Servlets, Spring MVC, HTML5, JavaScript,

CSS/Sass, JQuery.

Testing: JUnit, RSpec, Test::Unit. Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL. Cloud: Amazon EC2/S3, Heroku.

Tools: Git, Ant, Maven.

Scientific computing: Numpy, Matplotlib. OS: Unix/Linux, Mac OS X, Windows.

Teaching

Graduate Teaching Assistant

EXPERIENCE

University of Essex

Preparation, marking and teaching of classes and laboratories for the following undergraduate and postgraduate courses:

CE705 - Programming in Java, Autumn 2011.

CE320 - Large Scale Software Scale Systems and Extreme Programming, Autumn 2011.

 ${\rm CE}218$ - Computer Game Programming, Spring 2011.

CE152 - Object-Oriented Programming, Spring 2011.

CE705 - Programming in Java, Autumn 2010.

CE212 - Web Application Programming, Spring 2010.

CE112 - Procedural and Object-Oriented Programming, Spring 2010.

CE705 - Programming in Java, Autumn 2009.

AWARDS

Scholarship for MSc and PhD Computer Science degrees from the National Council of Science and Technology of Mexico.

PUBLICATIONS

- Coevolving Game-Playing Agents: Measuring Performance and Intransitivities. IEEE Transactions on Evolutionary Computation (2012).
- Learning Non-Random Moves for Playing Othello: Improving Monte Carlo Tree Search. IEEE Conference on Computational Intelligence and Games (2011).
- Fast Approximate Max-N Monte Carlo Tree Search for Ms Pac-Man. IEEE Transactions on Computational Intelligence and AI in Games (2011).
- A UCT Agent for Tron: Initial Investigations. IEEE Conference on Computational Intelligence and Games (2010).
- A Simple Tree Search Method for Playing Ms. Pac-Man. IEEE Symposium on Computational Intelligence and Games (2009).

CERTIFICATIONS

Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA), February 2006. Microsoft Certified Systems Administrator (MCSA), May 2007.

Work

Camisa Development Group (March 2006 - May 2007)

Experience

 $IT\ Systems\ Administrator$

Network Administrator, Windows Server 2003, Active Directory, VPN, CRM Software, Sage SalesLogix.

CANACINTRA (November 2005 - February 2006)

Internship

I developed a Web Application in ASP.NET/SQL SERVER for the management of the partners and registered companies in CANACINTRA.

URBI (June 2004 - August 2004)

Internship

Internal web applications with PHP, MYSQL, XHTML, CSS. Maintaining and development of internal applications in Java.

Installation of networking facilities.